# GIOVANNI BRUNETTI

Big Data and Software Engineer

 giovannibrunetti.it □ gb1609@outlook.com

github.com/GB1609 +39 3282498121

O Cosenza, Italy in linkedin

### SUMMARY -

I'm a computer scientist based in Italy focused on working in the Big Data context. I love writing code and solving problems with it!

I have been a Big Data Engineer since 2020 across multiple domains: energy, telecommunications and insurance.

SKILLS -

Technicals: GCP (BigQuery, Composer, DataFlow, BigTable,

ecc), Cloudera Ecosystem, Scala, SQL, Python, Scala, Bash, Docker, Kubernetes, Spark, Hadoop, Hive, Jenkins, Airflow, Kafka, Sonar-Qube, Git, Maven, Sbt, Functional Programming, HDFS, Team Tools and methodologies

(Jira, Confluence, Scrum)

Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Proactive, Team Working, Passion, Time Management, Challenge Seeker

#### **EXPERIENCE** -

**Big Data and Software Engineer** 10/2022 - NOW

Agile Lab

- · Consultant for a major Italian insurance company:
  - Data modelling and data partitioning in a Cloudera Platform ecosystem.
    - Defining and developing Spark job using Scala for Ingestion and processing real-time and batch data.
  - Development of NiFi pipeline to orchestrate jobs. MAIN TECHNOLOGIES: SCALA, SPARK, HIVE, IMPALA, SQL, POSTGRESSQL, HBASE, HDFS, BASH, SSH, JENKINS, KAFKA

01/2020 - 10/2023

### **Big Data and Software Engineer**

**VT Solutions Consulting** 

- · Consultant for a major German telecommunications company:
- Data modeling and data partitioning in a Google Cloud Platform ecosystem.
  - Defining and developing DataFlow job using Scala for Ingestion and processing real-time and batch
  - Development of Airflow DAGs using Python to orchestrate ETL operations on data for a DWH. MAIN TECHNOLOGIES: SCALA, PYTHON, BIG QUERY, COMPOSER, SQL, POSTGRESSQL, BIG TABLE, GCS, BASH, JENKINS, KAFKA, PUB SUB, AIRFLOW, SONARQUBE
- · Consultant for a major Italian telecommunications company. The main task was to write some guideline documents about the main approaches and best practices in a Big Data platform and its reference environment
  - Software component structure and code documentation.
  - Git integration Strategy (with particular focus on branching models like Git-Flow and GitHub-Flow, code and environment promotion).
  - Data Lake principles (data ingestion, data preparation, data exporting, testing).
  - Lambda architecture, data modeling, data preparation, partitioning.
  - Analysis for migration of Cloudera Ecosystem to Google Cloud Platform.
- · Consultant for a major Italian energy company.
  - Development of Apache Spark batch jobs using Scala for ingestion and processing of Avro file landed in HDFS.
  - Design and development of Data Quality Spark Processing Jobs for reports based on Hive and Impala.
  - Data Lake principles (data ingestion, data preparation, data exporting, testing).
  - Data preparation, data modelling and data partitioning.

MAIN TECHNOLOGIES: SCALA, JAVA, PYTHON, SQL, POSTGRESSQL, BASH, JENKINS, SONARQUBE

## CERTIFICATIONS

09/2012 - 10/2012

7/2022 - 7/2024 **GCP Professional Data Engineer Google Cloud** 

certified link

02/2022 Astronomer Certification for Apache Airflow Fundamentals and DAG Authoring Astronomer

certified link Fundamentals certified link DAG Authoring

PET B1 10/2023 **University of Cambridge** 

certified link

**Best Student Machine Learning** 10/2019 Università della Calabria - Department of Mathematics and Computer Science

certified link

certified link

Attendance course at ETC International College

ETC International College, Bournemouth, England

EDUCATION —			
2021	Master Degree in Computer Science Università della Calabria - Department of Mathematics and Computer Science		University of Calabria
2017	Bachelor Degree in Computer Science Università della Calabria - Department of Mathematics and Computer Science		University of Calabria
LANGUAGES —		DRIVING LICENCE	
English - B1+, Italian - native		Driving Licence: A1, B	